# Jeff Tseng (Yang-Che)

Email: jeffyct@cs.ubc.ca GitHub: jeff999955

Vancouver, BC V6T

Jeff Tseng is a research student at UBC specializing in computer vision and pursuing his master's degree. His main work revolve around Neural Rendering and SLAM, and he is currently working on diffusion models with Gaussian Splatting.

### **EDUCATION**

### The University of British Columbia

Master of Science, Computer Science

09/2024-

### The University of British Columbia

Research Assistant

2023-2024

### National Taiwan University

GPA 3.92/4.0

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Information Engineering

2019 - 2023

### **PUBLICATION**

### 3D Gaussian Splatting as Markov Chain Monte Carlo

NeurIPS 2024

Shakiba Kheradmand, Daniel Rebain, Gopal Sharma, Weiwei Sun, Jeff Tseng, Hossam Isack, Abhishek Kar, Andrea Tagliasacchi, Kwang Moo Yi

PointNeRF++ ECCV 2024

A multi-scale, point-based Neural Radiance Field

Weiwei Sun, Eduard Trulls, Yang-Che Tseng, Sneha Sambandam, Gopal Sharma, Andrea Tagliasacchi, Kwang Moo Yi

Orbeez-SLAM ICRA 2023

A Real-time Monocular Visual SLAM with ORB Features and NeRF-realized Mapping

Chi-Ming Chung, Yang-Che Tseng, Ya-Ching Hsu, Xiang-Qian Shi, Yun- Hung Hua, Jia-Fong Yeh, Wen-Chin Chen, Yi-Ting Chen, Winston H. Hsu

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### Computer Vision Lab, UBC

Vancouver, BC

Research Assistant

2023

- Explore the difficulty of 3D Gaussian Splatting on dynamic scenes on datasets such as DynamicScene, HyperNeRF, and DyCheck iPhone.
- Separately model static and dynamic Gaussians with optical flow masks and discover limitations when camera motion is large.
- Introduce Video Diffusion Model as a refiner to alleviate the sparse input issue from dynamic datasets.

PointNeRF++ Vancouver, BC

Research Intern 2023

- o Conducted experiments on KITTI-360, ScanNet, and NeRF Synthetic dataset for 3D Gaussian Splatting.
- o Explore the difficulty of 3D Gaussian Splatting on real-world scenes.

# Orbeez-SLAM (Communications & MultiMedia Lab)

Taiwan

Undergraduate Research Student

2022

- Used CUDA & C++ to migrate instant-ngp NeRF to ORB-SLAM to achieve **3D scene reconstruction** with **800x speedup** over other NeRF-based SLAMs.
- Derived rendering loss of NeRF in terms of camera pose and verify if the instant-ngp source code matches our derivation.

### Machine & Intelligence Understanding Lab

Taiwan

Undergraduate Research Student

2021 Fall - 2022 Spring

- Researched on enhancing Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) and Spoken Language Understanding through natural language pretraining.
- Arranged over 20 cross-modal (text and speech) tasks, their benchmarks, and datasets.

GoGoX Vancouver

Software Engineering, Data Scientist

Nov, 2022 - present

#### o Discrete-choice Stopping Model:

- \* Extracted the **Graphhopper** routing engine from the deprecated **JAVA** dispatch system, built the minimal version with **Docker Compose**, and provided a function in Python.
- \* Conducted **counterfactual analysis** on linear model which estimates the possibility of a driver to stop working by cumulative income, cumulative working hours, and other driver- or time-dependent factors.

### o GoGoX QA Bot:

- \* Design the RAG+LLM pipeline based on OpenAI, Pinecone, and Langchain to support customized ChatGPT with prompt engineering.
- \* Developed a minimum viable product (MVP) using **Streamlit**, allowing beta users to interact with the chatbot.
- \* Designed APIs to capture user feedback and responses, utilizing this data to enable memory-based conversations in the chatbot.
- \* Reduced a 2 second latency of Pinecone with a self-hosted Redis Stack vector database.

### • Working Time Labeling:

- \* Developed a linear model and automated the labeling process of pickup and arrival time.
- \* Conducted **feature engineering** on driver and order data for the linear model to identify the anomaly behavior of driver to help filter out cases unsuitable for labeling model.

### o GPS Map Matching:

- \* Employed Python shapely to determine which roads the driver is probably driving on the map given a GPS coordinate.
- \* Find the route with Hidden Markov Model with **Python** given possible road segments.
- \* Built a visualization tool with Python folium and OpenStreetMap to analyze the GPS track and users behavior.

### **ASUS Intelligence Cloud Service**

Taiwan

Software Engineering Intern

Jul 2022 - Sep 2022

#### o Selenium IDE Modification:

\* Added popup menu to a Selenium IDE by **Electron** and **Node.js** to support additional recording functions and **facilitate the testing** phase which **enabled 19** out of **23** testcases to be automatically recorded.

## Side Projects

- Clapping Detection: Examined and cleaned 4 different datasets labeled by actions, developed a model using PyTorch with 92% accuracy on Kinetics dataset, and adapted to a custom dataset of videos featuring children clapping.
- Draw-Straight-Line Detector: Developed an algorithm using traditional computer vision techniques such as contour detection and filtering to determine whether the subject in a video is drawing a straight line, implemented with OpenCV in C++.
- Open AIFab: Integrated 7 computer vision models implemented by PyTorch and Tensorflow into Flask as API for the backend team.
- Coughvid: Integrated audio models by Pytorch for cough detection and linear models for clinical data to a Flask API designed for COVID-19 cough detection.
- Japanese Memorizer App: Developed a vocabulary learning mobile application with Flutter, bloc, firebase backend, and the CI/CD pipeline on codemagic.
- **nvtop modification**: Added user filtering feature, in C, to an open-source GPU monitoring tool nvtop.
- LeaST: League Small Tool: Developed automation tools such as spam clicking and auto-accepting match invitation for League of Legends, implemented using C++ with Win32 API and Python with League Client API.